memsaab.com 2007-10-12

# Privacy Policy - Memsaab.com

|               | 

| ******Last updated: 15th January, 2007  **  
---  
  
Memsaab.com delivers content drawn from its partners and other sources, as well as providing access to message boards, chat sessions. Any information that you provide under memsaab.com services provided through the site may be collected and used by memsaab.com.

This statement sets out memsaab.com's policies relating to the collection and use of your personal information. It applies to your conduct on the memsaab.com website (“site"). These policies are in addition to memsaab.com 's general Terms of Use governing the memsaab.com and should be read in conjunction with such Terms of Use. 

******Contents:**  
---  
******Your personal information is important to us**  
---  

We recognise that your privacy is very important and that you have a right to control personal information. We know that providing personal information is an act of trust and we take that seriously. The following sections set out how we handle and protect your personal information and safeguard your privacy.   
  
******Site Membership**  
---  
  
memsaab.com has implemented a membership system which offers a more rewarding and personalised experience ("Membership"). To become a member and obtain the full benefits of Membership, you register your details with us and log in as a member each time you visit memsaab.com. (Membership is not necessary to access all parts of the website.) The benefits of Membership include: your own personalised home page on the site; e-mail newsletters; interactive tools and services and access to competitions. Also, to keep you up to date with what’s happening on the site, we'll send you member only offers from our selected partners and regular updates of our products and services.   
  
******How we collect information about you**  
---  
  
There are three main ways we collect information about you:  **If you are not or do not log in as a site member  **  
Whenever you visit memsaab.com, our servers automatically record information about your usage of the site, such as the time of the visit, its duration and the pages you visit. This is to help us understand what parts of our site users enjoy the most and to help us ensure that advertisements on memsaab.com are most directly relevant to your interests. If you have not identified yourself on the site, such as by registering for Membership or logging in as a member, the information we collect about you remains anonymous.  **If you log in as a site member**  
Once you have become a site member, we collect personal information about you in order to provide you with the full benefits of Membership. When you first register for Membership, we collect information from you such as your e-mail, name and suburb, and will continue to add to your member profile as you interact more on the site, for example, if you enter a competition or subscribe to our newsletters.  **If you enter into a competition**  
When you enter into a competition on the site, you may be prompted to sign in to Membership. This will streamline the entry process, as many of the competition entry fields will be pre-populated with information we already hold about you. You may be required to provide further information to satisfy the entry conditions. If the competition is being sponsored by an advertiser, you may be prompted to opt-in to receive further promotional material from that third party. If you consent to this, then at the end of the competition, we will provide the information on your entry form to that third party. Use of your personal information will be in accordance with this Privacy Policy as well as that of the third party. The URL or contact details for third party privacy policies will appear in the competition terms and conditions.  
  
******How we preserve your privacy**  
---  
  
We understand that even with our Privacy Policy, some people will not feel comfortable disclosing personal information in order to become a site member. If you don't feel comfortable disclosing your real identity but still want to take advantage of site Membership, you can register for Membership using a pseudonym (or "nym") - a different name. This way, you choose your own nym, which might be "Radhika Chopra" or "Sony Sharma", and that's what we will call you. We won't know who you really are, but we will still be able to find out what you like most on our site and therefore give you the many enjoyable and customised experience of the site possible. If you wish to receive all the benefits we give to our members, you have to provide correct information which can be verified by us before giving you more privileges on our site.   
  
******Our use of cookies**  
---  
  
Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies. However, if you do not wish to receive any cookies, you may set your browser to refuse them (for more information on disabling cookies, click here). In some instances this may mean you will not be able to take full advantage of parts of the site. 

The use of cookies can enhance your enjoyment of what we offer, because they help us personalise your experience of our site by providing information which is most relevant to your interests. Cookies provide us with aggregated information on how users interact on our site, track which advertisements are effective and help us improve your site experience. We also use cookies to operate the Membership system, as they help us identify visitors to the site who have previously registered. Cookies do not personally identify you, but your browser. 

We use the independent tool Urchin to measure and analyse Internet usage across the site. The Urchin tracking code collects the following core information on usage of the site:   
The number of page views (or page impressions) ;   
The number of unique visitors;   
How long these unique visitors (on average) spend on the site   
Common entry and exit points into the site.   
This aggregate, non-personal information is collated by Urchin and provided to us to assist in analysing usage of the site. The Urchin data is also accessible by media organisations and research companies for the purpose of conducting industry comparisons with other Internet portals. 

All pages on the site are coded with the SiteCensus software. This is transparent to the user, as the software makes use of an invisible image (via Javascript) or an invisible Java Applet*, at the bottom of the web page. This software stores a cookie in your browser, which contains a unique identifier. This enables Urchin to track the number of unique visitors to the site. In no way does this unique identifier identify a user personally. We do not and will not marry any data collected by Urchin with any personal information collected on the site. 

Urchin software code cannot be disabled entirely on the memsaab.com pages, as the SiteCensus code takes into account all web-browser configurations, including the disabling of Java and Javascript. However, if cookies are disabled in your browser, then Urchin cannot track you as a unique visitor and will consider you a new visitor each time you browse a new page on the site. To learn how to disable your cookies, refer to the beginning of this section. 

*The use of Javascript and/or Java Applet is dictated by the browser you use. Typically, Internet Explorer users with Version 4 or above will use the Javascript method. Netscape users or users whose browser does not support Javascript 1.1 will use the Java Applet method.   
  
******How we use and disclose your information**  
---  
  
We will not disclose any information about you without your consent unless it is:   
Required by law;   
We believe it necessary in order to provide you with a service which you have requested;   
We suspect that your use of the site is in breach of the Terms of Use;   
To protect the rights or property of memsaab.com, any memsaab.com user or any member of the public; or   
To lessen a serious threat to a person's health or safety. 

We will never share your personal information with a third party or allow a third party to promote its products and services directly to you without your explicit consent.   
  
******Communicating with site members:**  
---  
  
service messages and promotional messages we send to you  
We send our members service e-mails which contain important information about updates, changes and developments on the site, such as if we take down a service which we know you are currently using, or, if we have improved a service and want to communicate its new functionality to you. For you to continue to make the most of what’s available on the site, it is essential that we send these communications. 

From time to time, we will send you member-only offers from our carefully selected partners, e-mail newsletters to which you have subscribed, and tell you about new competitions. 

You can manage the type of information you receive from us by:   
updating your Membership profile;   
unsubscribing from the message you receive; or   
e-mailing us on our privacy feedback form (please allow seven days for this request to be processed).   
  
******How we store your information and keep it secure**  
---  
  
We will take all reasonable steps to keep secure any information we hold about you and to keep this information accurate and up to date. Your information is stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities. 

In addition, our employees and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by us. However, we will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access to your personal information. 

You can also play an important role in keeping your personal information secure by maintaining the confidentiality of any password and accounts used on the memsaab.com. Please notify us immediately if there is any unauthorised use of your account by any other Internet user or any other breach of security.   
  
******How you can access your information**  
---  
  
If you are a memsaab.com member, you can access, change and update your Membership profile at any time on the site. If you wish to know what other information we have gathered about you while you have been logged in to the site, you can request this information via our privacy feedback form. We will endeavour to respond to your request within seven days. If you make us aware of any ongoing concerns or problems with our site, we will take these issues seriously and work to address these concerns. You can contact us by sending us email at [ privacy@memsaab.com](mailto:privacy@memsaab.com)  
  
******Changes to the Privacy Policy**  
---  
  
Our commitment to make memsaab.com the leading website for women means that we are constantly adding new sites and features to the site. We will continuously review our Privacy Policy to ensure that it protects your privacy while supporting your user experience on the site. We encourage you to keep visiting our Privacy Policy to see if any updates have been made.   
  
******Further information on privacy**  
---  
  
For more information about privacy issues, visit the website on Federal Privacy Policy;
